Let's take a look at the relationship of fuel efficiency
我们来探索一下燃油效率
against another variable, manufacturing year.
与另一个变量 (生产年份) 的相关性
With improvements in technology and increasing environmental concerns have
随着科技进步 人们对环境的关注日益加强
cars running under conventional fuels seen recent increases in fuel efficiency.
促使常规燃料汽车近来不断提高燃油效率
Let's start by looking at a scatter plot of
我们先来看一个散点图：
combined fuel efficiency against year like we tried last time.
燃油效率 vs 生产年份 创建方式和之前一样
The regression line that got fit suggests a slight upward trend in efficiency,
从拟合回归线可看出 效率有小幅提高的趋势
but this is not clear from the data.
但从数据来看 这点并不明确
The only point that we can really make out are those above about 42 miles per gallon.
可以明确辨认出的 是在 42 英里每加仑 (mpg) 以上的那些点
This is a clear place for us to make use of transparency and jitter settings.
很显然 我们得调整透明度和抖动设置
Let's start with jitter.
先来设置抖动
Since we want to jitter the x values,
因为我们想抖动 x 的值
we add the x jitter parameter.
所以得添加参数 x_jitter
The value 0.3 means that each x value will be
参数值设为 0.3 也就是每个 x 值
adjusted randomly up to 0.3 more or 0.3 less.
随机抖动范围在 ± 0.3 之间
It should be noted that this only works with
注意 该设置只能用在
Seaborn's regplot function and not in matplotlib's scatter.
seaborn 的 regplot 函数中 不能对 matplotlib 的scatter 函数使用 则不能
The points now get arranged in strips with some width,
现在数据点呈宽带状
rather than just a single line.
而不是线状
But this is still not enough to really see the distribution of points below the mid 30s,
但这样还是看不出 35 以下的数据分布
we should now add some transparency.
所以要进行透明度设置
If we were working with matplotlib's scatter function,
如果用的是 matplotlib 的函数 scatter
we could just add a parameter alpha directly to the function call.
那我们可以直接在调用函数里添加 alpha 参数
With regplot, we instead need to set the parameter in
而用 regplot 函数的话 我们得先把这个参数写为字典形式
a dictionary set to the scatter KWS parameter.
然后将这个字典赋给 scatter_kws 参数
Alpha takes a value between zero and one that specifies the opaqueness of points,
alpha 会在 0 和 1 之间取值 从而指定数据点的不透明度
zero is fully transparent and one is fully opaque.
0 是完全透明 1 是完全不透明
Let's start by trying and alpha of 1/5.
我们先试着把 alpha 设为 1/5
It's a good start, but
挺好的
the interesting areas in the center is still pretty indistinguishable.
但中间的目标区域趋势还是难以辨别
What if we try an alpha of one-twentieth,
我们试着把 alpha 设为 1/20
we can see the trend in the points a little bit better now.
这下可以比较清楚地看出数据点的趋势了
Darker areas naturally come about as an outcome of transparent points overlapping,
有一定透明度的数据点重叠 会形成颜色较深的区域
and these areas slightly rise in value across the years.
这些区域随着年份增长 稍有上升
Note that through all of this,
注意 这一系列操作
the regression line hasn't changed a bit.
并不会改变回归线
The jittering and transparency don't affect
抖动和透明度设置
the underlying values for the purposes of regression line fits.
不会影响形成拟合回归线的基础值
If you're still feeling unsatisfied with the result of all this,
如果你对这样的结果还不满意
there's still more alternative ways of plotting the data.
那还可以用别的办法来绘制数据
For example, since year is discrete,
比如 既然年份是离散的
we might treat it as a categorical variable and
那我们大可以将其看作分类变量
use a different plot type that you'll see later on.
绘制成另一种图表 下个视频见